export const BIOLOGYA2018 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The scientist who introduced binomial nomenclature in the classification of organisms was",
A: "Carolus Linnaeus.",
B: "John Ray.",
C: "Charles Darwin.",
D: "Louis Pasteur.",
answer: "A. Carolus Linnaeus.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of the following statements is true about arthropods?",
A: "Prothorax bears only, wings",
B: "Prothorax bears only legs",
C: "Metathorax bears only wings",
D: "Mesothorax bears only legs",
answer: "B. Prothorax bears only legs",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. What level of organization is Spirogyra?",
A: "Tissue",
B: "Organ",
C: "Organ system",
D: "Cell",
answer: "D. Cell",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The streaming movement of cytoplasm within Paramecium is known as",
A: "transpiration.",
B: "cyclosis.",
C: "osmosis.",
D: "digestion.",
answer: "B. cyclosis.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Which of the following organelles is found only in plant cells?",
A: "Lysosomes",
B: "Ribosomes",
C: "Plastids",
D: "Mitochondria",
answer: "C. Plastids",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Active transport differs from diffusion in that active transport",
A: "takes place in both light and dark reactions of photosynthesis.",
B: "is a very fast process.",
C: "allows the movement of substances against concentration gradient.",
D: "occurs in both plant and animal tissues.",
answer: "C. allows the movement of substances against concentration gradient.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The type of response demonstrated is",
A: "phototropism.",
B: "thigmotropism.",
C: "geotropism.",
D: "hydrotropism.",
answer: "D. hydrotropism.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The conclusion drawn from the experiment is that",
A: "leaves of plants are positively phototropic.",
B: "shoots of plants are negatively geotropic.",
C: "roots of plants are positively hydrotropic.",
D: "shoots of plants are negatively thigmotropic.",
answer: "C. roots of plants are positively hydrotropic.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The odontoid process is found on the",
A: "sacral vertebra",
B: "axis vertebra.",
C: "thoracic vertebra.",
D: "atlas vertebra.",
answer: "B. axis vertebra.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. A seedling was made to stand in a solution of red ink for three hours and a transverse section of the stem was examined under the microscope. The process being investigated was",
A: "ascent of water through the xylem.",
B: "diffusion of coloured substances.",
C: "the importance of microelements to plants.",
D: "distribution of food in plants.",
answer: "B. diffusion of coloured substances.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following structures would carry out respiration? A",
A: "dry leaf",
B: "germinating cowpea",
C: "decolorized leaf",
D: "boiled cow pea",
answer: "B. germinating cowpea",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Which of the following substances is not an excretory product of animals?",
A: "Carbon dioxide",
B: "Sweat",
C: "Oxygen",
D: "Urea",
answer: "C. Oxygen",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. An example of homeostasis in living organisms is",
A: "root hairs of a plant growing towards a source of light.",
B: "the release of phosphorous into the phloem of a plant growing in a phosphorus-deficient soil.",
C: "changing of the body colour of chameleon to match the colour of the foliage on which it is resting.",
D: "cooling effect resulting from evaporation of water from the body surface.",
answer: "B. the release of phosphorous into the phloem of a plant growing in a phosphorus-deficient soil.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "C. Bowmanâ€™s capsule.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The thyroid gland is located at the base of the",
A: "neck.",
B: "midbrain.",
C: "kidney.",
D: "liver.",
answer: "A. neck.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following statements about the response of neurones to stimulus is correct? The",
A: "intensity of stimulus must reach a threshold value before the neurone can be excited.",
B: "neurones respond to stimuli of any strength.",
C: "neurones respond more rapidly during the absolute refractory period.",
D: "neurones respond to all stimuli applied in rapid succession.",
answer: "A. intensity of stimulus must reach a threshold value before the neurone can be excited.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following practices may lead to infection of the eye? Use of",
A: "concave lenses",
B: "contact lenses",
C: "biconcave lenses",
D: "convex lenses",
answer: "B. contact lenses",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The structures for gaseous exchange in breathing roots are",
A: "lenticels.",
B: "mitochondria.",
C: "cuticle.",
D: "stomata.",
answer: "A. lenticels.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The adult insect in this life cycle is",
A: "housefly.",
B: "mosquito.",
C: "butterfly.",
D: "cockroach.",
answer: "C. butterfly.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The larva is also known as",
A: "maggot.",
B: "caterpillar.",
C: "nymph.",
D: "chrysalis.",
answer: "B. caterpillar.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The source of energy required by plants during food production is",
A: "chlorophyll.",
B: "sunlight.",
C: "photosynthesis.",
D: "microorganisms.",
answer: "B. sunlight.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. One major difference between plant and animal nutrition is the ability of plants to synthesize",
A: "water for animals.",
B: "water for plants.",
C: "food for plants only.",
D: "food for plants and animals.",
answer: "D. food for plants and animals.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. By what process is starch converted into maltose?",
A: "Photosynthesis",
B: "Condensation",
C: "Hydrolysis",
D: "Translocation",
answer: "C. Hydrolysis",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The ascent of water in tall trees is mainly due to",
A: "adhesive forces.",
B: "cohesion forces of water molecules.",
C: "transpiration pull.",
D: "root pressure.",
answer: "C. transpiration pull.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The duodenum of a person was surgically removed. Which of the following food substances would have their digestion affected?",
A: "Starch, protein and lipids",
B: "Starch and protein only",
C: "Starch, peptones and maltose",
D: "Starch and lipids",
answer: "A. Starch, protein and lipids",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following dental formulae represents the dentition in rabbits?",
A: "zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
B: "zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
C: "zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
D: "zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The property of soil demonstrated is",
A: "colour.",
B: "particle size.",
C: "capillarity.",
D: "texture.",
answer: "C. capillarity.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of the following statements would be a correct observation at the end of the experiment? Water moves",
A: "highest in clayey soil.",
B: "lowest in loamy soil",
C: "highest in sandy soil.",
D: "to the same level in all soil types",
answer: "A. highest in clayey soil.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The most important factor(s) that influence(s) the ecological niche of an organism is/are the",
A: "physical environment.",
B: "food and water availability.",
C: "competition for food and space.",
D: "water, light and predator-prey relationship.",
answer: "C. competition for food and space.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The most important factor needed by the organisms is",
A: "oxygen",
B: "light energy.",
C: "low humidity.",
D: "nitrate.",
answer: "B. light energy.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following instruments is used to determine the turbidity of water?",
A: "Secchi disc",
B: "Hygrometer",
C: "Hydrometer",
D: "Rain gauge",
answer: "A. Secchi disc",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. In an ecosystem, the least efficient energy transfer link is from the",
A: "producer to primary consumers.",
B: "secondary consumers to decomposers.",
C: "primary consumers to secondary consumers.",
D: "sun to producers.",
answer: "B. secondary consumers to decomposers.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Xerophytes have the following characteristics aimed at conserving water except",
A: "thick cuticle",
B: "broad leaf surfaces.",
C: "sunken stomata",
D: "waxy cuticle.",
answer: "B. broad leaf surfaces.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. An association between living organisms in which one lives on and feeds at the expense of the other is known as",
A: "parasitism.",
B: "commensalism.",
C: "predation.",
D: "mutualism.",
answer: "A. parasitism.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. When large numbers of organisms share limited space and resources: the immediate result is",
A: "immigration.",
B: "emigration.",
C: "extinction.",
D: "competition.",
answer: "D. competition.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following diseases is caused by a bacterium?",
A: "Ringworm",
B: "Syphilis",
C: "Malaria",
D: "Poliomyelitis",
answer: "B. Syphilis",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Conservation of wildlife is necessary mainly because",
A: "wild species cannot resist diseases better than their domesticated species.",
B: "many people derive pleasure from observing wild animals.",
C: "many predator wild animals help in the control of pests.",
D: "it prevents the extinction of species.",
answer: "D. it prevents the extinction of species.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Patients X and V were likely transfused with blood of genotype",
A: "BO.",
B: "AO.",
C: "AA.",
D: "OO.",
answer: "A. BO",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. What should the hospital have done to prevent patient X from showing the symptom described above? Patient X should have",
A: "been asked for the blood group.",
B: "been screened for HIV.",
C: "undergone an agglutination test.",
D: "undergone malaria test.",
answer: "C. undergone an agglutination test.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The greatest contribution to genetic studies was made by",
A: "Thomas Morgan.",
B: "Robert Hooke",
C: "Charles Darwin.",
D: "Gregor Mendel.",
answer: "B. Gregor Mendel.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The exchange of genes between homologous chromosomes is called",
A: "test cross.",
B: "back cross.",
C: "mutation.",
D: "crossing over.",
answer: "D. J",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which parent mouse is heterozygous for coat colour?",
A: "M",
B: "K",
C: "L",
D: "J",
answer: "D. crossing over.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Which of the offspring are all homozygous?",
A: "S",
B: "Q",
C: "R",
D: "P",
answer: "A. S",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Genes that remain linked are those",
A: "close to each other on the chromosomes.",
B: "on the same locus on the chromosomes.",
C: "on the homologous chromosomes.",
D: "which are allelic pair.",
answer: "A. close to each other on the chromosomes.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. A plant cell has 14 chromosomes prior to mitosis. What is the number of chromosomes in the daughter cells?",
A: "56",
B: "28",
C: "14",
D: "7",
answer: "C. 14",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The chemical bond that holds the bases of the two strands of DNA together is",
A: "electrovalent bond.",
B: "oxygen bond.",
C: "hydrogen bond.",
D: "covalent bond.",
answer: "C. hydrogen bond.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Who proposed the theory in the illustration?",
A: "Louis Pasteur",
B: "Robert Hooke",
C: "Jean Lamarck",
D: "Gregor Mendel",
answer: "C. Jean Lamarck",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The theory supports",
A: "natural selection.",
B: "the use and disuse of body parts.",
C: "independent assortment.",
D: "struggle for survival.",
answer: "B. the use and disuse of body parts.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. In evolution, fossils are naturally preserved in",
A: "chemicals.",
B: "rocks.",
C: "water.",
D: "trees.",
answer: "B. rocks.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Which of the following insects is not a social insect?",
A: "Ant",
B: "Termite",
C: "Honeybee",
D: "Housefly",
answer: "D. Housefly",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]